<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items>
<item><problem></problem><solution></solution></item>
<item><problem><value>1. PC Overheating</value><value>2. Dysfunctional USB Port </value><value>3. PC keeps disconnecting from WiFi</value><value>4. PC beeps</value><value>5. PC Fans not working</value><value>6. PC not using a portion of RAM</value><value>7. Overworking fan</value><value>8. PC crashes before loading the OS</value><value>9. PC isn’t powering on</value><value>10. Noisy PC</value><value>11. Noisy hard drive</value><value>12. Blue Screen of Death</value><value>13. Blank monitor</value><value>14. Monitor goes black after few seconds</value><value>15. Keyboard issues</value><value>How to Fix Mouse Left-click Malfunction in Windows</value><value>Rounding up</value><value>You might also like</value></problem><solution><value>You don’t have to run to the repair shop every time your PC ends up with an issue. Many of the </value><value> have a </value><value>, and you can </value><value>.</value><value>To help you troubleshoot common PC problems yourself, I have listed 15 most common PC hardware problems and </value><value> if you face any of them.</value><value> </value><value> A </value><value>. Additionally, PC components may also get permanently damaged due to constant exposure to heat. </value><value>There are </value><value>, i.e. either the cooling system isn’t working properly or the PC is heating to the point your cooling system can’t handle it anymore. In either case, I have written a comprehensive article on different </value><value>. Do check it out. </value><value>If your USB port stops working, it’s not necessary that it’s broken</value><value>. Below are some solutions that can fix this issue: </value><value>Restarting the PC is the answer to many problems, and it is a common solution to USB port problem as well. </value><value>Uninstalling the driver of the USB port will force Windows to reinstall it when you will restart the PC. This may fix the problem. Here is how to do it: </value><value>USB Selective Suspend is a Windows power saving feature that </value><value>. Sometimes it could stop a USB port from working. Here is how to disable it: </value><value> This option should be kept enabled if you want to save battery power. If it </value><value>.</value><value>If your Wi-Fi is working fine but your PC keeps disconnecting from it, then your PC’s network card may not be receiving full power</value><value>. Windows has a </value><value>. You need to disable this feature: </value><value>The PC </value><value>and sounds beeps in different rhythms to tell you. Here is an article on </value><value>. </value><value> If the PC doesn’t start after the beeps, then it’s usually difficult to solve the problem yourself. However, I’m going to list down two of the most common problems due to which beeps occur, and thankfully, you can solve them yourself as well.</value><value>A problem I recently dealt with. If the </value><value> and won’t boot at all. The solution is simple, open up the PC (laptop users should let an expert handle this) and </value><value>. Here’s how:</value><value>This video should help you properly install the RAM</value><value>A damaged or </value><value>. Take out any newly added hardware components and see if it solves the problem. If the PC works fine afterward, then either </value><value> (or replaced). </value><value>If you notice one or more fans in your PC aren’t working, then it could be due to the dirt inside. You will have to open up the PC and </value><value> to clean up the fans and other components. </value><value>Here’s a video to help you with the cleaning process:</value><value>If dirt wasn’t the problem, then you can also use the </value><value> app to see what is the problem. The </value><value>. Although your PC motherboard must support fan control to use this app.</value><value>Sometimes your PC may not use a portion of RAM. For example, </value><value>. This is usually a Windows setting issue.</value><value>If only a few MBs (200-400MB) of RAM isn’t being utilized, then it’s probably being used by PC hardware and you can’t do anything about it.</value><value>The solution to this problem is simple – </value><value>. Here is how to fix it: </value><value>While you are at it, you should also check the checkbox next to </value><value> option and ensure your PC is utilizing all the CPU cores as well. Set it to the maximum number if you want to use all of the CPU power. </value><value>If this didn’t fix the problem, then </value><value>. Try reinstalling it.</value><value>Your PC fan </value><value>. The higher the temperature, the faster the fan will run. In case your PC temperature is fine (you can use </value><value> to check it), but the fan is running at full speed; then you’ll have to manually control it.</value><value>You can use the </value><value> app for this purpose as well. It will </value><value> so you can manage their speed. Don’t worry about app compatibility, overworking fan problem only happens with motherboards that can control the fans.</value><value>If your </value><value> right before it was supposed to load the operating system, then it’s a </value><value>. As the OS is unable to load, then either the RAM is corrupted and can’t hold the boot loader or the </value><value> and can’t load data inside it. </value><value>If you have multiple RAM slots, then </value><value> will help find the culprit. In the end, you will have to replace the corrupted RAM or the hard disk, whichever has the issue. </value><value>If your PC is not powering on at all – not even a single light in it, then it must be a problem with the power source. </value><value> If your PC’s </value><value> are working fine, then the problem may be with the PC’s power cable. </value><value> (if you don’t have a spare) to see if it turns on. You’ll have to get a new power cable if this fixes the problem. </value><value> Take out the battery and put it back  before starting the laptop. If this doesn’t work, then </value><value>. Start the PC on charger power and see if it works. You will have to replace the battery if it fixes the problem.</value><value> You should also remove all types of external devices connected to your PC while trying this. A malfunctioning device might cause this issue.</value><value>If you hear a lot of extra noise while using the PC, then most probably it is a plea to clean it up. </value><value> to clean it up yourself. If you have overclocked your PC GPU and CPU, then they could be the reason for the noise as well.</value><value>Here is a video with simple methods to clean your PC:</value><value>There is also a chance that </value><value>. You can check this article about all the </value><value> for more information. </value><value>If you hear </value><value>, then it might be time to get a new one. Hard drives have a limited lifespan and </value><value>. You can use </value><value> to check the health of your hard drive. The tool will tell you the current health of the hard drive with signs like "Good", "Caution" or "Bad". </value><value>You should </value><value> immediately and </value><value> before this one fails on you. </value><value>The dreaded Blue Screen of Death (BSOD) can occur </value><value>, but usually, it’s a hardware problem. Whatever the cause, BSOD requires immediate attention as it’s a </value><value>. </value><value> is a great </value><value> that will show important information if you have recently suffered a Blue Screen of Death. You should be able to identify and solve the problem using this information. Below are some common reasons for BSOD and their solutions. </value><value> </value><value>A corrupt driver may be the cause of BSOD. To find that out, use the following steps:</value><value>You can also use a third-party app like </value><value> to automatically find and fix driver problems. </value><value>If you </value><value>, then it may freeze the system and show BSOD. For that, you should either stop opening too many programs or upgrade the RAM. </value><value>BSOD is also a </value><value>, use the instructions in problem #11 above to identify hard disk problems. </value><value>Heating PC also leads to BSOD if </value><value>. Use the instruction in problem #1 to solve it. </value><value>If your monitor isn’t showing anything, then this could be a </value><value>. You should connect the monitor to another PC to see whether the problem is with the PC or the monitor. </value><value>If the </value><value>, then replace the power cable with a working one and see if it helps. Here is a good article on </value><value>. </value><value>If the monitor goes black after few seconds of display, then it could be a problem with the</value><value>. Press the auto-adjust button on your monitor to see if it fixes it. If not, then you will have to </value><value>. </value><value>You can </value><value>. Pressing the auto-adjust may show the display for few seconds. You can use this to your advantage and adjust the color while pressing auto-adjust.</value><value>If your keyboard is </value><value>, then there is no problem with the keyboard. You must have enabled toggle keys and filter keys in Windows settings that cause such a problem. To disable them: </value><value>
						Left-click of your mouse is the most used function that helps open files and programs and confirm commands...						</value><value>Many of the above </value><value>. However, some of them will definitely require you to pay a visit to the computer repair shop. </value><value>It’s good to at least know what is wrong with your PC so </value><value>. Do let us know in the comments if you faced any PC hardware problem before and how you solved it. </value></solution></item>
<item><problem></problem><solution></solution></item>
<item><problem></problem><solution><value>Hongkiat.com (HKDC). All Rights Reserved. 2020</value><value>Reproduction of materials found on this site, in any form, without explicit permission is prohibited. </value><value> &amp;dash; </value></solution></item>
</items>